

## SYSTEM SECURITY ENGINEER · SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURE RESEARCHER · SOFTWARE REPOSITORY MINER

731 Lexington, New York City, NY 10022, U.S.

□ (+1) 213-884-8846 | ■ ducmle@usc.edu | # lemduc.io | □ lemduc | □ lemduc | ⑤ lemduc

## Summary\_

Blends research experience in Software Engineering, Data Mining, and System Security with diverse and practical trainings in the software industries of Vietnam, S.Korea and U.S. to offer solid skills in software design and development. Experiences include (1) mining software repositories/big data, (2) system security, (3) architecture design, recovery, and analysis, (4) software product line engineering.

Los Angeles, U.S.

Aug. 2013 - July. 2018

Pohang, S.Korea

Hanoi, Vietnam

Aug. 2010 - May. 2012

Aug. 2005 - May. 2010

## **Education**

**University of Southern California (USC)** 

PhD in Computer Science, Software Architecture Research Group (SoftArch), GPA: 3.87/4.00

Pohang University of Science and Technology (POSTECH)

MSc in Information Technology Convergence Engineering, Software Engineering Lab (SELab), GPA: 95.9/100.0

Hanoi University of Science and Technology (HUST)

BSc in Information Technology (Magna Cum Laude), GPA: 8.07/10.00

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN - EV.CLOUD PROJECT, PLATFORM TEAM

Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Bloomberg L.P. New York, New York, U.S.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER July. 2018 - PRESENT

**NEC Laboratories America, Inc.** Princeton, New Jersey, U.S.

RESEARCH INTERN - COMPUTER SECURITY GROUP May. 2017 - Aug. 2017

**Veritas Technologies LLC** Culver, California, U.S. May. 2016 - Aug. 2016

**Samsung Research America** Irvine, California, U.S.

RESEARCH INTERN - ADVANCED PRINTING SOFTWARE LAB Jun. 2015 - Sep. 2015

**Dasan Handysoft** Seoul, S.Korea

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2013

**HDC Media Vietnam** Hanoi, Vietnam PHP DEVELOPER & ASTERISK PBX ADMINISTRATOR Aug. 2009 - Jun. 2010

Skills

**Programming** Java (Proficient), Python, Linux Shell, JavaScript, C/C++

**Frameworks** Spark, Spring, OSGi, EMF, GWT, Joomla, Liferay, Microsoft Azure

**Databases** MySQL, MongoDB

Others Agile Development, MTFX, SVN, Git, Asterisk PBX

Relevant Coursework

Software Engineering Advanced Algorithms Machine Learning Database Systems

Software Architecture Artificial Intelligence Natural Language Processing Information and Data Modeling

Decision Support Systems Software Testing Advanced Operating Systems Information Security

Honors & Awards\_

Best Paper Award, ICSA 2018 2018 Seattle, WA, USA

2016 'Thesis in Three' - Best Presentation Award, Doctoral Symposium, ICSE 2016 Austin, TX, USA

2015 Awardee, ACM SigSoft CAPS Travel Support for attending ICSE 2015 Florence, Italy

2014 Awardee, USC Doctoral Student Summer Institute Award Los Angeles, CA, U.S.

2013 Awardee, Vietnam Education Foundation Fellowship U.S.

2011 Best Poster Prize, 3rd International Symposium on IT Convergence Engineering Pohang, S.Korea

2010 Awardee, Research Scholarship from National Research Foundation of Korea Pohang, S. Korea 2010 Awardee, Certificate of Merit for Excellent Graduation Achievement Hanoi, Vietnam

Duc M. Le · Curriculum Vitae **SEPTEMBER 15, 2019**